翻译：阿蘅阿蘅  猫中之王  醉芝士
校对：出口成章赛太公  断章取义YY猫  总监   YY猫
后期：孤帆     时间轴：加森
老爸老妈浪漫史
第九季  第十一集
星期六  下午5点
马修和马文正坐着长途车
Marshall and Marvin were taking the bus
离婚礼还有25小时
赶来长岛和我们见面
on their way to Long Island to meet up with us.
马文乖乖
There, there, little Marvin.
眼泪拜拜
Let no more tears fall.
很快就要  见到妈妈
We're gonna see mommy in no time at all.
你好  很抱歉吵到你了
Hello there. I'm sorry for all of the noise.
今天把我们都折腾坏了
It's been a long day for the Eriksen boys.
-你说话为啥要押韵  -很高兴你注意到了
- Uh... What's with the rhyming? - I'm glad that you ask.
哄我儿子睡觉  是一件苦差事
To get my son sleeping is no easy task.
几周前  这是我妻子的事
A few weeks ago, the job fell to my wife.
当我儿子哭个不停时
And as the poor baby cried out for dear life,
她就一直读书  但是全不管用
she read every book, but all were no use
直到读到《鹅妈妈》  于是突然起作用
until she arrived at a mother named Goose.
-马文你为什么  -她注意到了
- Why, Marvin... - She noted.
原来押韵的故事书会让你想睡觉
...these rhymes make you tired!
从那开始  马文睡觉
And ever since then, all young marvin's required
只需一本押韵故事书  便能片刻乖乖进梦乡
is one book of rhymes, and to dream land he goes.
我现在读点啥呢
Now, what shall we read?
糟了  我的书忘在车里了
Oh, crap, I left his book in the car!
完蛋了
That blows.
不是吧  真是太倒霉
Oh, no, what a bummer!
运气真太背
What craptastic luck!
押韵书一没  旅途注定累
Without marvin's rhyme book, this ride's gonna suck!
请问在座哪位有诗集
Does anyone here have some poetry maybe?
或者给点建议也可以
Or any advice?
我的建议就是别生孩
Yeah! Don't have a baby!
如果不想让小马文醒过来
I guess if I don't want young Marvin to wake up,
唯有自己编个押韵故事来
the rhymes will just have to be ones that I make up.
我要秒速内编起小诗歌来
I'll whip up some poetry in seconds flat!
《体育报》
纽约大都会球队惨败
我知道了
Oh, I know!
这个故事叫《莫斯比出击》
This story's called Mosby at the bat!
莫斯比出击
泰德爱情不顺  前情十分堪忧
The outlook wasn't brilliant for poor Ted's romantic life.
即使年近四十  依旧没有老婆
He was deep into his thirties, and yet, still he had no wife.
突然就在某天  他在学校改卷
But then, one day whilst grading papers,
命运将他作弄
life sent him a whammy.
物理教授名丽萨
A physics prof named Lisa
家乡乃是迈阿密
who'd just moved here from miami.
教授
Professor?
她腼腆地叫声他  他回答
She asked timidly. He answered:
叫我泰德
Call me Ted.
我无意打扰你
I don't want to bother you.
-请坐  -他说道
- Please, have a seat. - He said.
我是新来教师  想来寻求建议
I'm fairly new to teaching, and I'm looking for advice.
每晚我都试讲  偶尔试讲两回
Every night I practice giving lectures, sometimes twice.
但每当教磁力
But when I teach Magnetic force,
学生迷茫眼放空
I just see eyeballs glazing.
于是我到处打听  你的教学人人夸
I asked around, and people say your lectures are amazing.
声名远扬口碑佳
Which is really saying something,
毕竟建筑学  乏味又无趣
Because, architecture? Yawn.
泰德想的是
And Ted thought...
听你在胡扯  物理就"有趣"
Psh, yeah, 'cause physics is so interesting.
继续
Go on.
你的经验丰富
It's just that you're so skilled,
而我刚刚起步
And I'm a relative beginner.
如果不嫌弃  请你吃顿饭
If it isn't too much trouble, can I take you out to dinner?
只求能给些建议  绝不耽误你时间
I'd love to get some pointers, and I shouldn't keep you late.
不知你意下如何
What do you say?
你问我意下如何
What do I say?
西区泰德有妞啦
Teddy westside's got a date!
-万岁  -我们欢呼
- Hooray! - We cheered.
泰德离开冷板凳
Ted's off the bench!
小子重回泡妞场
Our boy's back in the game!
谢天又谢地  可怜小泰德
Thank God, it's been a hundred years
寂寞了百年
since Mosby scored a dame.
上回见咪咪
The last time he saw boobies was
是在数年前
the screen-test scene in Fame.
他的前女友
The last girl he dated,
就是"右手党"
I think "Righty" was her name.
打住  不要太兴奋
Hold it. Let's not all go crazy
鸡血打太早
like some wild Berzerkers.
今夜的约会  或许纯属同事情
What if this is just a business meal between co-workers?
泰德细思量  往日失败约会情
Ted thought back on past failed dates.
哎哟我的妈  这话有道理
Oh, God, that could be true.
多少回我自作多情一人归
How many times have I come home to find my balls are blue?
若要有戏唱  全都取决你们俩人
It all depends where Ted and his new fetching young floridian
处于子午线的何处
are standing in relation to that puzzling meridian
这条国际"日"界线
called "The international date line."
没错  我的新理论
That's right, new theory.
-你们问这是什么  -没人问
- "What's that," You ask? - Nobody did.
让我细细道来  约会子午线
I'll now address your query! The date line
约会  不是约会
幸福伤心分界线
is the border betwixt happiness and sorrow.
这边  今夜孤独回家
On this side, you go home tonight.
那边  你明天性福归来
On this side, home tomorrow.
就在此时此刻  巴尼说尽下流话
And then, as Barney made some gestures that were rather rude,
泰德心中忐忑  出发去见丽萨
Ted left to go meet Lisa, in a rather puzzled mood.
这算是个约会吗
Was this a date?
他的心中无定数
He simply couldn't tell how he was faring.
丽萨来了
Then lisa showed up.
泰德见她衣着便觉有戏唱
Ted rejoiced to see what she was wearing.
若是同事情
For girls at business dinners
领子绝对高
don't have necklines that revealing!
约会
但只跟他握手
But then a friendly handshake gave poor Ted
泰德深觉不妙
a sinking feeling.
不是约会
然后开始吃饭
And so, the night wore on.
性福之球旋转
And back and forth, the globe rotated.
泰德心痒难耐
But still, Ted's curiosity was never fully sated.
到底结局是何
How long could this continue?
一切听天由命
He was truly fortune's pawn.
直到丽萨看电视
Then Lisa saw the TV.
是洋基队的比赛
Hey, the Yankees game is on!
-棒球...  -泰德观察到
- Of baseball... - Ted observed...
你好像挺懂
...You seem to have some firsthand knowledge.
她耸肩说道
To which the lady shrugged and said...
曾打过垒球
I played softball in college.
标准女人装懂球
Now the age-old softball stereotype's just that,
我就不再多说明
and nothing more.
-好样的  -洋基队得分后
- Yeah! - But as the Yankees got a run,
泰德自己难"得分"
Ted feared he wouldn't score.
我们一度以为泰德
For while the date side of the line's
今夜能抱得美人归
the one we all might guess he's in,
但怕丽萨喜欢错队
there'll be no joy in tedville if our Lisa is a...
泰德是克利夫兰印第安人队的粉丝
赞  我们赢了
Yes! We win!
丽萨喝一口酒后说
Then Lisa took a drink and said...
这话可能有点荒谬
This may sound kind of random,
但喜欢洋基有原因
but there actually is a reason for my rabid Yankee fandom.
今天就跟你说实话
I guess I'll just be honest here,
虽然这话听来疯狂
though crazy it may seem.
刚来纽约时  曾与队员"玩"
My first week in New York, I dated someone on the team.
谁
Which player?
-我不会说的  -拜托
- I'm not saying. - Please?
你是八卦记者吗
What are you, a reporter?
泰德开始胡思乱想
Ted's mind began to race.
服务生走近要点菜
The waiter came to take their order.
当丽萨说
As Lisa said...
我要意大利沙司
I might like the spaghetti marinara.
泰德心里想的是
Poor ted just wondered silently...
马里亚诺・ 李维拉[洋基队员]
Mariano Rivera?
当她说
And as she said...
听说这里鸡肉面条沙拉好
I read this place has great chicken milano.
泰德想的是
All Ted could bring himself to think was:
阿方索・索利安拉[洋基队员]
Alfonso Soriano?
我想吃点有营养的
I want something hearty.
来份味噌鳕鱼吧
How about blackened miso cod?
乔・吉拉迪[洋基教练]
Is it Joe Girardi?
我了个去  是罗德里格斯吗[洋基巨星球员]
Holy crap, is it A-Rod?!
行了  泰德  冷静
Okay, ted, calm down.
给自己打打气
You've got to get yourself together.
微笑  帅气
Just smile, be charming,
表现出超凡的魅力  聊聊天气
ooze charisma, talk about the weather.
这次可能是个约会
For this might be a date,
也就是说可能会有愚蠢的言行
which means there might be hanky-panky.
冷静  镇静  别...
So, dude, be cool, relax, don't even...
快点告诉我是谁
Just tell me which Yankee!
我不想在这里说
I'd rather not discuss this here.
不过  我也不想
But then again, I'd hate...
让秘密破坏约会
to let a silly secret ruin such a lovely date.
约会
既然问题明摆着
If there's an elephant in the room,
我们解决掉便可
why don't we just remove it?
是德瑞克・吉特[洋基队长]
I dated Derek Jeter.
我有照片能证明
Here's a picture that'll prove it.
泰德看向那照片
As Ted looked at that cell phone pic,
心中有了两答案
there were two things he reckoned.
这次肯定是约会
This definitely was a date,
吉特
但绝不会有下次
but there wouldn't be a second.
看  有用
See? It worked.
我就说几句押韵  乖乖儿子就睡着
I said some rhymes, and out my boy did conk.
终于能享受旅程
Now let's enjoy the ride.
让开  混蛋
Move, jackass!
我需要一个新故事来哄马文睡觉
Okay, I need a brand-new tale to silence Marvin's chatter.
上一个故事的内容不太适合小孩啊
I don't know, that last one had some sketchy subject matter.
抱歉  你坐车之前
Forgive me, but before you got here,
抽了大麻是不是
did you smoke a joint?
你怎么能给孩子讲这么蠢的故事
You don't tell kids a tale that crass!
我觉得他说得对
I guess he had a point.
我知道  我讲的东西
I know, I said some things that were,
的确是有点问题
As you say, kind of questionable.
其实像马文这么大的孩子
The truth is, children Marvin's age
不太容易被影响
Aren't really that impressionable.
那你可否会记得  在这个年龄发生的事情
Do you remember anything from when you were this small?
三岁的时候摘南瓜  是我记得的第一件事情
Pumpkin picking at age three is the first thing I recall.
他不会记得这个故事  没错
He won't remember this. I guess it's true.
最好别记得
It better be.
如果送马文看心理医生
Or else we'll end up paying
可得花掉我一大笔钱
through the nose for Marvin's therapy.
兄弟  聊得愉快  但我要去睡了
Okay, buddy, nice chat, but I think I need a break.
兄台请便
Great idea.
接下来的故事是
After this story!
罗宾抢了大蛋糕
Robin takes the cake.
东区有家蛋糕店
Once in an east side bakery,
罗宾阿姨进店里  客人纷纷注目礼
Your debonair aunt Robin was making other customers think,
哪里来的女汉子
"Geez, who let this slob in?"
罗宾丝毫不在意
She didn't care about their stares, or who was looking on.
她与某男刚分离
She'd just broke up with...
凯文
Kevin.
不对  是盖尔  还是史酷比
No, Gael. Or Scooby?
或者是唐
Don?
好事不成双
Now, sometimes, when it rains it pours,
坏事不单行
and sometimes, it starts snowing,
正当奶油满衣裳
For as cream filling hit her shirt...
罗宾  最近过得怎么样
Hey, Robin, how's it going?
从前男友又现身
'twas Simon, her ex-boyfriend
却是加拿大西蒙君
from her younger days in Canada,
西蒙翻身大变样
But now, he looked quite different...
押韵
Rhyme.
开动脑筋
Uh... Thinking. Uh...
哥们刚收到新消息
I've just been handed a news flash.
加拿大这词难押韵
The word "Canada" is unrhymeable.
宁可烂醉爬公牛
It's easier to-- I don't know--
胜过为此想破头
get drunk and try to climb a bull.
问世间多少好汉
But Canada, damn it, ask any man on the planet
被加国无情摧残
And watch their stammerin' stamina
笨嘴拙舌胡乱编
as they clamor and cram it into the middle of a sentence
唾沫横飞编不圆
for a shot at repentance,
一心只恨语文差  无奈留待后人搞
Pass the problem on to all their non-rhyming descendants.
呜呼  加拿大之难  难于上青天
I've never met anyone who could clean up after Canada.
唯我唐尼扫地叔
Except my uncle Tony from the Bronx.
有志扫出一片天
He's a janitor.
臭显摆啥啊
Show-off.
西蒙  见到你真高兴
Simon. Nice to see you.
你怎么来纽约了
So, what brings you to New York?
-我住在纽约了  -真的吗
- I live here now. - What? Really?
-真的  -真是好哇
- Yeah. - That's great.
给我个叉
Can I get a fork?
西蒙向来没前途
He'd always been a deadbeat
标准加国装逼男
and your classic hoser phony,
看到西蒙新气象  罗宾不由心慌慌
But seeing Simon all cleaned up hit Robin like a zamboni.
罗宾朝他细打量
And as she looked him up and down,
心里又起小波浪
Young Robin felt a tingle.
莫非西蒙终奋起
Had Simon blossomed finally?
不知现在独身否
And if so, was he single?
太好了
So great.
语气立刻变柔弱  眼眸闪动送秋波
She purred, whilst batting her eyelashes like a flooze.
我和玛莎订终身
Yup, I'm engaged to Louise Marsh,
按摩浴缸装家里
And our pad's got a jacuzz!
面包店里  黯然无光  地板塌方
The bakery spinned, the floor dropped out.
空气沉重  犹如糖浆
The air was thick as syrup.
可怜罗宾  两眼发晕  呼吸困难
Poor Robin swooned, she couldn't breathe,
眼眶泛红  泪光闪闪
her eyes began to tear up.
欲寻借口赶紧溜
And as she tried to stammer some excuse
西蒙开口把话提
to get away, Simon said:
看我的婚礼蛋糕多牛逼
Our wedding cake is pretty bitchin', eh?
罗宾伤心又失意  最蠢主意心头起
And so was born the worst idea poor Robin's ever had.
泰德家中房门响
And on Ted's door there came a rapping.
我干了一件坏事
I did something bad.
罗宾坐下说经过
As Robin told her tale,
泰德得知她犯错
Ted knew she'd made a massive boo-boo.
罗宾偷婚礼蛋糕  这错实在太离谱
For stealing someone's wedding cake is terribly bad juju.
罗宾  你居然堕落至此  气死我了
Robin, I'm beside myself to see what you've become!
赶紧把蛋糕给我还回去
You must return this cake at once!
-我办不到  -为什么
- I can't! - Why not?
因为
'cause...
太好吃
Yum.
泰德看到此恶行  吓得倒吸一口气
Ted gasped, for he had never seen a brazen act so vicious.
罗宾心中很自责  同时
Robin felt remorse, and yet...
蛋糕美味难舍弃
Oh, God, this is delicious!
一口两口三四口  五口六口十七口
So one piece led to two, then three, then five, then 17.
金刚狼残暴附体  大蛋糕惨遭蹂躏
She savaged that poor cake like some rapacious Wolverine.
又啃又咬大口嚼  狂乱之夜灯摇摇
Eating, gobbling, munching, so the frenzied night wore on.
等至你妈把门进
And by the time your mom arrived,
半只蛋糕已殆尽
The cake was halfway gone.
我一接到消息马上就来了
I came as soon as I got word.
事情到底有多糟糕
So how bad is the damage?
你自己看吧  蛋糕被她摧残成这样了
See for yourself the product of her cake-in-gullet crammage!
只剩一半了
Half a cake?
我都做了什么呀
What have I done?!
全世界皆不原谅
The world shall not forgive it!
一失足成千古恨
This day will live in infamy.
耻辱永远跟随我
I never shall outlive it!
我是传说中那个
For I have become
靠暴食掩饰情感  你可千万别搞错
the girl that eats her feelings, don't mistake it.
我得迅速站起身  免得等会椅子坏
I think I need to get out of this chair before I break it.
你这只超级蠢猪  说的哪门子疯话
Nonsense! Hogwash! Balderdash!
你妈心怀好意把话说
Said mommy, with great fervor.
革命尚未成功  同志必须再战
You can't stop now, for don't you see?
对于不知情的旁人  这并不算是放不下
To the uninformed observer, you're not some sad cliche,
由女性撰写并面向二、三十岁的单身女性的文学作品
更不是鸡仔文学中的悲惨剩女
some loser from a chick-lit story.
只要吃完这半个  恢复荣光分分钟
You're Robin, and you're half a wedding cake away from glory!
如果此刻就放弃  西蒙赢得了胜利
If you quit now, then Simon wins,
传奇只能终於此
The tale comes to a stop
因为偶遇前男友  你的脑子不利索
at how you saw an ex, freaked out,
抢走蛋糕回家吃
and robbed a pastry shop.
但是我的好闺蜜  如果你还有勇气
If you have the guts, my dear,
此时不战待何时
it's time to get empowered
竭尽全力战蛋糕
and be remembered for this
传奇便流芳百世
sweet behemoth you devoured.
多年以后的今天
And years from now,
行吟诗人高声唱
the troubadour will raise his voice and sing
战蛋糕记美名扬
of the time that Robin took the cake.
美
And ate the whole...
名
Damned...
扬
Thing.
罗宾再次冲上战场
Once more into the breach she surged,
泰德和你妈加油打气
as Ted and mommy cheered
蛋糕高如山  慢慢消灭完
and bite by bite the towering confection disappeared.
朋友得消息  纷纷来围观
Some friends were called to come and watch.
人人都爱看
And no one had to beg.
围观变派对
It soon became a party.
巴尼还带酒
Barney even got a keg.
一勺接一勺  罗宾战香草
Forkful after forkful, Robin guzzled french vanilla,
吃声惊天地  比猩猩还吵
making noises not unlike those made by a gorilla.
加把劲  罗宾  吃完它
Come on, Robin, finish it.
你妈在一旁鼓励
Mom's exhortations rang
此景就像阿波罗
like Apollo coaching Rocky
教洛基打大棒槌
'gainst a frosted clubber lang.
《洛基四》  我的最爱
Oh, Rocky IV, my favorite.
不对  《洛基四》是对阵俄国人
No, no, IV is with the Russians.
不对  《洛基四》是他因脑震荡
No, IV's the one where he talks weird
说话怪腔怪调
because of his concussions.
-洛基说话一直这样  -好了
- I think that's all of them. - Hey now,
-不要吵架好吧  -就是《洛基四》
- no need to be discordant. - It's Rocky IV.
-是《三》  -是《二》
- No, III. - No, II.
真没必要为这个吵
It's really not important.
其实就是《洛基三》
决胜时刻终于到来  罗宾还剩最后一口
At last young Robin raised the final bite up to her lips
人群纷纷静默无言
The crowd grew still.
只闻巴尼大嚼薯片
The only sound was Barney eating chips.
只剩下最后一口
Just one bite left.
这场景简直就是《铁窗喋血》
Hey, this is like that scene from Cool Hand Luke. You know,
“这孩子能吃下五十个鸡蛋”  对不对
"My boy can eat 50 eggs." Right?
她马上要吐了
She's gonna puke.
但罗宾没有吐
But Robin did not puke.
她咽下了蛋糕  骄傲地站起来
She ate that bite and stood up, proud.
等等  还没有结束
Wait. I'm not done yet.
她对震惊观众说
She shouted, to the startled crowd.
我虽消灭了蛋糕
I've bested this here wedding cake.
我既骄傲又自豪
I'll gladly wear that crown.
但我要有始有终
But now that I have done that task
让蛋糕冲下食道
it's time to wash it down.
今夜已如此美妙
For it's been such an awesome night,
让我来锦上添花
there's just one way to cap it.
喝下这整桶啤酒
I'm going to drink this entire keg.
巴尼  开闸
Okay, Barney, tap it.
如今没人会记得  罗宾那晚被人甩
And now that night's remembered not for Robin getting dumped
人们记得的只是  最后送她去洗胃
But as the night we took her in to get her stomach pumped.
快看
And look at that,
这小天使终于睡着了
The little angel's sleeping soundly, Gus.
令人头痛的问题终于
Looks like our problems...
你到底要开哪条道
Pick a lane!
我恨这台蠢巴士
I hate this stupid bus.
马文啊  今夜漫漫苦煎熬
Marvin, I'm afraid this night is not much of a winner.
交通堵塞不流畅
Stuck in traffic, now we've missed
彩排晚餐赶不上
the whole rehearsal dinner.
希望你不要记得
I pray that I was right and that you'll have no memory
这趟旅途超傻逼
of this godforsaken ride down the congested LIE.
不过我可以保证
At least we know one thing for sure:
事情不会更糟了
Things can't get worse, I swear.
永别了  休息站的煎饼包
Adios, truck stop burrito. Ooh!
后面厕所一团糟
Do not go in there.
算了  再讲一个故事
Okay, one more story,
我尽量把它讲好
and I'll try to tell it pretty.
巴尼・斯丁森
The tale of Barney Stinson,
纽约泡妞王传奇
Player king of New York City.
巴尼・斯丁森  纽约泡妞王传奇
某日麦氏酒吧里  众友齐聚于一堂
Once upon a time, we all went out to get our drink on.
恰逢一女走进来
When who should walk in but a girl
身着粉色毛衣装
with sweater tight and pink on.
佳人坐下喝啤酒
She ordered up a beer.
故事发展不难猜
I think you see where this is going.
巴尼表达最直白
As Barney put it, oh so eloquently:
奶妹胸前抖啊抖
Boy-oy-oy-oing.
他对此妞感兴趣  起身就要往前走
He rose to go approach this girl commanding such intrigue
可你老妈叫住他
When mommy interrupted:
老兄  你肯定泡不到她
Dude, she's way out of your league.
她一没穿超短裙  二没穿爆乳服装
She's not in daisy dukes, nor squeezed into a hooters tee.
三无塑体会员卡
And I don't see a Curves membership
挂在钥匙上咣当
dangling from her key.
四没做喷雾晒黑
She has no glaring spray tan,
五没独角兽纹身
no unicorn tattoos.
她在浅尝霞多丽
She's sipping chardonnay,
而非豪饮樱桃酒
not pounding cherry-flavored booze.
脸上妆没有哭花
Her makeup isn't running,
更没有搔首弄姿
she's not playing with her hair.
"进"身机会实在小
There's very little chance she'll let you put it anywhere.
我接受你的挑战  莉莉
Your challenge is accepted, Lil.
对巴尼・斯丁森来说
There is no girl too pretty,
这世上哪有无尘女神
for I am Barney Stinson,
我可是纽约泡妞之王
Player king of New York city.
你不能给自己扣上王的高帽子
You can't anoint yourself the king,
就像那个混蛋勒布朗一样
just like that jerk, Lebron.
他三年前就离开骑士队了
He left the Cavs three years ago.
兄弟  别想了  往前看吧
Bro, give it up, move on.
我为什么是泡妞之王  很高兴你们问了
So why am I king? Glad you asked.
-我们没问  -从未问过
- We didn't. - Never do.
原创故事时间到
It's origin story time.
相信我  字字千真万确
And trust me, every word is true.
很久以前的某个早上  我在臣服者身边醒来
One morning long ago, I woke up next to a conquest.
这女孩妙处着实不少  她的咪咪
So many great things 'bout this girl: Her boobs,
她的乳房  她的胸部
her rack, her chest.
她乃久旱渴甘霖
She had a thirst for action,
巴尼奋身扑欲火
and young Barney was a-quenchin' it.
这是故事的重要部分吗
Is this important to the story?
不  只是觉得应该提一下
No, just thought I'd mention it.
接着我离开房间  与丰满女说拜拜
As I departed, having bid this busty babe buh-bye,
我停下来四处看  忍不住停下发呆
I stopped and looked around, and wondered:
我究竟身在何处
Where the hell am I?
路标上写着22街  我的担心渐退
The sign read 22nd street, and my concern decreased
直到冷风吹树枝
until a cold wind blew a branch aside,
赫然露出"东"这字
revealing: "East."
东区  不
The east side. No.
我做了什么啊
Wh-what have I done?
我懊恼支吾着
I stammered with chagrin.
一辆黑色轿车停在面前
Just then a black sedan pulled up...
-你是巴尼吗  -是的
- You Barney? - Yeah.
上车
Get in.
有一句话是真吗
Is any of this true?
当然是真的  现在  下巴别掉下来
Of course. Now, hang on to your "chayers."
那日之会  我以前也曾参加过
For that day I was called before...
泡妞好手的最高议会
The high council of players.
非常感谢各位  亲自出席会议
Gentlemen, for your attendance here, our deepest thanks.
我遗憾地宣布  议会有人偷猎
I'm sad to say, this council has a poacher in its ranks.
斯塔顿岛罗
燕尾服查理  布朗克斯区唐尼
机长比尔
泡菜罐鲍勃
这位巴尼
For Barney here
在他的领域外泡了妞
picked up a girl outside his territory.
东区
The east side
是燕尾服查理的地盘
is Tuxedo Charlie's turf.
他很生气
He's mad.
千真万确
True story.
2004年的协议中  曾很明确地规定
The agreement of 2004 quite clearly did define
我们猎艳分界线  就定于第五大道
Fifth avenue to be our hunting grounds' dividing line.
我绝不会"停船"到  西区的大学女生
Your west side college girls are not the slip I park my boat in.
你也应该明白
So you should know
东区的懵懂少女  你也绝不能染指
my east side debutantes are quite verboten.
议会成员
Members of the council...
兄弟们  没人想要开战
Bros... nobody wants a war.
我当然没有忘记2004年的协议
Of course I've not forgotten the agreement of '04.
我能说什么  一次愚蠢之举
What can I say? A bonehead move.
为自己辩护  我无话可说
Defend it? I'm not able.
但是兄弟们  难道对在座的
But, bros, have I not been a bro
兄弟们来说  我不够兄弟吗
to each bro at this table?
布鲁克林的朋友  泡菜罐鲍勃
My friend from Brooklyn, pickle jar Bob,
可以为我作证
will give some validation.
记得想找宾州车站
Remember that young tourist
那位年轻女游客吗
who was looking for Penn Station?
她刚从波士顿过来
She'd just come in from Boston,
一脸床技好的模样
had a wicked good-in-bed look.
我给她指错了方向  她去了红钩区[布鲁克林]
I gave her bad directions and she ended up in red hook.
-闭嘴  巴尼  -布朗克斯区唐尼
- Shut up, Barney. - Whoa, Bronx Donnie,
别这么激动
Let's not get excited.
这里被踩到头上的  不止燕尾服查理一人
Tuxedo Charlie's not the only one here who's been slighted.
你为了上她  就告诉她你是基特[洋基队队长]
You told her you were Jeter in your quest to lie upon her.
冒充洋基队是我的专长
Impersonating Yankees is my thing.
你还要不要脸啊
Have you no honor?
先生们  请不要破坏
Gentlemen, please, let's not blow
现在和谐的气氛
this detente to smithereens.
议会允许机长比尔发言
Council recognizes Captain Bill,
来自皇后区的兄弟
our bro from Queens.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们都认识我
You all know me,
尊重我的伎俩
and you all respect my game.
我扮成飞行员  在行李处泡妞
I dress up like a pilot and meet girls in baggage claim.
我从61街伍德赛德  坐地铁大老远而来
And on my long-ass subway ride from 61st and Woodside,
在路上我想到办法  为让你们不伤和气
I came up with a plan to keep you on each other's good side.
巴尼  你对不起他们两位
Barney, you have wronged these two.
为了弥补他们的损失
So, for the game they're losing,
现在你必须允许他们
you now must grant them each
各选一位西区的美女
a west side hottie of their choosing.
开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
这是和解办法吗
That's the settlement?
拜托  这样够傻的
Come on, that's rather silly.
先生们  请表态
Gentlemen, what say you?
我要罗宾
I want Robin.
我要莉莉
I want Lily.
得了吧  布朗克斯区唐尼
Please. Bronx Donnie?
他决不可能泡到我
No chance he could get me in the sack.
麻烦转告下黑手党  我认识有妞他能搞
Tell that mafioso I know something he can whack.
女士们  不用担心
Ladies, don't you worry,
你们俩的玉腿  依旧可以紧闭
your fair legs can all stay closed.
因为幸好他们
'cause luckily they took
接受我的还价
the counteroffer I proposed.
先生们
Well, gentlemen,
看来我说什么都不能动摇你们了
it seems there's nothing I can say to sway you.
查理  唐尼
Charlie, Donnie,
别再说了  我很乐意补偿你们
Say no more, I gladly will repay you.
卡洛塔  上香槟
Carlotta, some champagne.
我们休会前  先来干杯吧
Let's toast before we all adjourn.
敬咪咪
To boobies.
顺便说下
Oh, and b-t-dub,
酒里有毒
y'all just drank poison.
玩死你们
Ha-burn.
于是  我的朋友们  我
And thus, my friends, I have become,
以血腥手段成为
through methods somewhat gory
纽约市泡妞之王
The player king of New York city.
赞
Boom.
故事讲完了
The end.
真实故事
True story.
太精彩了
Well, that was great.
你的传奇小故事  让我们哄堂大笑
Your little story tickled all our ribs.
但你犯了个错误  先生
But one mistake you made, sir,
忘了先喊妞归你
was forgetting to call dibs.
不  这不公平
No! Not fair.
我才是泡妞之王
But I'm the King.
-穿衣品味比他好  -对不起  哥们
- And such a better dresser. - Sorry, dude,
这是为了报复你
But that's revenge
先上了教授丽莎
for Lisa the professor.
咱们再喝一轮吧
Let's have another round.
你妈咪说
Your mommy said.
于是我们又喝了一轮
And so we had one.
夜渐渐深了  我得说
The night wore on, and I must say,
那晚还不错
it wasn't a half bad one.
多美好的记忆  我们年轻快乐的心
What memories. Our young and happy hearts
热情似火一般
were hot as fire.
那些日子似乎  已经恍若隔世
Feels like a lifetime since those days.
对不起  各位
Sorry, folks,
爆胎了
Flat tire.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
我永远到不了南塔克特岛了
Now I'm never gonna make it to Nantucket.
烟花表演
Oh, look a fireworks display.
火箭之光烟花
Some rockets red glare action.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
我以为眼中景象  全怪青光眼药水
Thought my glaucoma drops were causing a reaction.
马文  对不起这次旅途超级波折
Marvin, I'm so sorry this whole journey's been a bummer.
很快你会回到妈妈的怀抱  温暖如夏
Soon you'll be right back in mommy's arms, as warm as summer.
可悲的是  我们到达旅馆的那刻
But sadly while your troubles stop once we get to the inn
就是你的麻烦结束  我的麻烦开始的那刻
the moment we arrive is when my troubles will begin.
有时候爸爸们做错事
Sometimes daddies screw up,
有时候妈妈们会生气
sometimes mommies get upset.
这个周末的记忆  我真心希望你会忘记
I really hope this weekend is a memory you'll forget.
快看天上的烟花  享受坠落的火光
So look up at those fireworks, enjoy the falling embers...
孩子们  这是你们的马文哥哥
And that, kids, is the very first thing
记得的第一件事
your cousin Marvin remembers.
女士们先生们  还要等一小时
Gentlemen and ladies, it'll be an hour or so...
拖车才能到达
before the truck gets here to give our
把坏巴士拖走
broken bus a tow.
我建议大家都把自己弄得舒舒服服的
So in the meantime I suggest we all get nice and cozy.
我们得待上一段时间
We're gonna be here for a while.
做个玫瑰花环游戏如何
Uh, ring-around-the-rosy?
转圈游戏  唱到"蹲"时  最后蹲的出局
好的
Yeah!
这里离法汉普顿旅馆有多远
How far do you suppose it is to the Farhampton Inn?
我想五英里外吧
I'd say about five miles away.
不是吧
Oh, no.
你笑什么
What's with the grin?
于是马修抬起头望向天空
Then Marshall looked up heavenward,
对着天上第一颗星星发誓
and swore by night's first star
说了他很快后悔的五个字
five simple words he'd soon regret:
我能走着去
I can walk that far.